so today we're going to continue our
所以今天我们要继续我们的
study of virtual memory by looking at in
通过查看虚拟内存的研究
more detail at how how address
如何如何的地址 详细
translation works and then and and then
翻译工作，然后和再
we'll learn about how virtual memory
我们将学习如何虚拟内存
works on real systems on Linux and x86
适用于Linux 和x86的实际系统
64 systems and the payoff for that is
64个系统和回报因为 这是
that you'll really be able to now
那你就真的能现在
understand how fork and exec really work
了解如何fork和exec真正发挥作用
and how how vital the virtual memory
以及如何如何重要的虚拟内存
system is due to these sort of the
系统是由于这些种类的
entire working of the system so let's
该系统的整个工作让我们
look at some specific examples of how we
看看 我们 如何的一些具体的例子
do address translation and here's that
做地址转换和这里的那
reference slide so let's suppose we have
参考幻灯片让我们假设我们有
this simple memory system with fourteen
这个 简单的存储系统 十四个
bit virtual addresses twelve bit
位虚拟地址为12位
physical addresses page size of 64 bytes
的64个字节的物理地址页的大小
so in our we have so we need six DPL
所以在我们的我们，所以我们需要 六个DPL
bits offset bits and then the remaining
位偏移的比特，然后将余下
bits are the virtual page number and
位的虚拟页 序号和
similarly for our physical addresses we
同样，对于我们的物理地址，我们
need we need six offset bits and the
需要我们需要六偏移位 ，
remaining bits form the physical page
其余位形成有形的网页
number okay now are that the TLB in this
数还好现在的TLB在这
in this system has 16 entries and it's
在这个系统中有16个 入口，它的
4-way set associative so remember that
4路集联，以便记住
the TLB caches page table entries okay
在TLB缓存 好吗 页表项
and those page table entries are
而那些页表项
uniquely identified by the virtual page
通过 虚拟页唯一标识
number so we only need to use the VPN to
号码，以便我们只需要使用 VPN 来
to access entries in the in the TLB we
访问条目中的TLB 我们
have 16 entries 4-way set associative so
有16项4路集联等等
there's a total of four sets and so we
共有四套 ， 所以我们的
use the low order the two low order bits
使用低阶两个低位比特
and the VPN as the index and then the
和VPN作为指标，然后将
remaining bits just like any other cache
其余位就像任何其他的缓存
or the tag bits
或标记位
okay and then this we've initialized
好吧，然后这我们已经初始化
this with some some various values now
这与一些一些不同的值现在
notice that the actual contents of the
注意到的实际内容
the TLB are in this tree in this region
在TLB在这棵树在这个区域
here right so the this set this is just
这里的权利， 因此这一套 ，这只是
to help identify what set there there's
帮忙鉴定一下设置有有
no entry called set with a value of zero
没有条目 称为设定值为零
right we just was just we're just
正确的，我们 只是刚刚 我们只是
identifying that as a as a yeah
鉴定为 作为耶
just--we're just explicitly listing the
只是- we're 只是明确列出
index and so each of our entries in the
指数在如此我们每一个条目
TLB consists of this tag and if the if
TLB由这个标签的，如果当
the TLB entry is valid a physical page
TLB项是有效的物理页
number okay now we also need a page
还好现在数量我们还需要一个页面
table so we'll have we'll assume that we
表，所以我们需要我们假定我们
have this page table with we're just
在此页面表 ，我们只是
showing the first 16 entries and the
示出第一16 项和
each page table entry consists of a
每个页表项包括的
physical page number and a valid did it
物理页面数和有效的 做到了
valid bit is on then then that indicates
有效位上 ，然后再指示
that the page is in memory and and the
该页面是 在 内存 中 ，与
PPM field gives the physical page number
PPM字段给出物理页号
okay and again there's there's no actual
没关系， 再有没有实际
this VTN column doesn't actually exist
这VTN列 实际上 并不 存在
in the page table okay and now we have a
在页表没关系，现在我们有一个
simple simple direct mech direct mapped
简单简单直接的机甲直接映射
cache it's addressed with physical
缓存它与物理寻址
addresses like and it contains 16 sets
地址等，它包含16套
each with one line and we'll assume a
每一个热线，我们将承担
four byte block size so we have so we
四字节的块大小，所以我们有那么我们
have a four byte block size so we need
有四个 字节的块大小，所以我们需要
to offset bits for the cache 16 sets we
以抵消比特 缓存16套我们
means we need for cache index bits and
意味着我们需要缓存索引位和
then the remaining bits are
然后将剩余的比特是
for the tags now just it's just an
对于标签现在只是它只是一个
accident of the way that I defined this
那我 定义这个 途中发生意外
the system that the cache tags are
该系统的缓存标签
exactly the same as the physical page
完全一样的物理页面
number so this this this is just the
号码，以便这这这仅仅是
coincidence and it doesn't isn't
巧合，并没有不
necessarily that way okay now with the
现在没事了与一定是这样
magic of av audio-visual systems switch
AV视听系统 的魔法切换
good
好
okay so let's we're going to look at
好了，让我们要去的看
this a couple examples using this this
这个使用这个这几个例子
little system okay now so let's suppose
好一点的系统现在让我们假设
the CPU executes an instruction that
CPU执行指令
generates an effective address it's a
产生这是一个有效地址
virtual address of 0 X 0 3 d 4 and then
的0的虚拟地址X 0 3天4，然后
it passes that to the MMU
它 传递的是对MMU
which is needs to figure out the the
这是需要 弄清楚的
corresponding physical address and then
对应的物理地址，然后
it needs to fetch the data from cache or
它需要 从缓存中 读取数据， 或者
memory okay so what's the first thing we
内存好了，什么是 第一件事情 ，我们
do is we just write out the bits for
做的是我们刚写出来的位
this virtual address okay and then we
这个虚拟地址好，然后我们
identify the different fields okay so we
识别不同领域的好，所以我们
have the offset virtual page offset bits
有偏移虚拟页偏移位
and then the remaining bits of the
然后的剩余位
virtual page number okay
虚拟页码 好吗
the offset in this case is 2 4 0 X 2 for
在这种情况下 ，偏移量是2 4 0 X 2为
the VPN is F and then we have that the
该VPN是F，然后我们的
two TLB I bits which are 1 1 so 3 and
2 TLB余位，而这1 1 SO 3和
then we have the tag bits which are also
那么我们有标记位，而这 也
equal to 3 so the first thing that the
等于3这样的第一件事是 ，
MMU does given this address is it checks
MMU不给这个 地址是 检查
the TLB on hoping that the page table
在TLB上希望页表
entry that it needs is cached in the in
它需要进入的中缓存
the TLB so it goes extracts the index
在TLB如此这般提取指数
bits 3 and that gives us
位3和 给我们
so now that that says that if this page
所以现在是说，如果这个页面
table entry is in the TLB it's going to
表项是它要的TLB
be in set three okay so so we go to set
在一套三好吧，所以我们去设定
three and now we're looking for an entry
三，现在我们正在寻找一个条目
in set three with a with a tag of three
在设定了三个有带 三个 标签
okay so we go across this one there's
好了，我们去跨越这一个有
four entries in this here's an entry
在这所四个项目的一个条目
with a tag of seven that's not ed and
与这不是编的七个标签和
plus the valid bits zero
加上有效位为零
oh here's a here's an entry with a tag
哦，这里有一个在这里的 一个标签 的 项
of three and a valid date of one so
三， 一如此的有效日期
we're luck we lucked out the page table
我们的运气，我们运气好页表
entries in the TLB and so the the TLB
在TLB等等的TLB项
returns the value the physical page
返回值 的物理页面
number which is zero D back to the MMU
这是零 ð回 MMU数
which can now construct the physical
现在可以构造物理
address so it constructs that physical
地址，以便构建 物理
address PA by copying directly copying
通过复制直接复制地址PA
the VPO bits to the PPO bits okay right
在VPO位的PPO位 好 权
as we discussed the last time that the
正如我们 所讨论的是最后一次了
virtual page offset is always identical
虚拟页偏移总是相同的
to the physical page offset because the
物理页面 ， 因为 偏移
block size is in the virtual address
块大小 是在 虚拟地址
space in the physical address space of
在物理地址空间 空间
the same size okay so here so we get the
同样大小没关系所以在这里，所以我们得到了
low order ppl bits and then the physical
低阶 PPL位 ，然后在 物理
page number which came which comes from
里面传来页码其中来自
the PT e that's cached in the TLB is
该公司 在TLB缓存 PT e 是
zero XD and so that forms the PP n bits
零XD并且使得形成PP n位
of the physical address so they cut
物理地址，因此他们削减
these these now constitute our our
这些现在这些构成了我们我们
physical address so now the next step
物理地址所以现在的下一步
once we have the physical address is to
一旦我们的物理地址是
look to send that to the cache and ask
看发送到缓存，并 要求
the cache to return the value at that
缓存在返回值
address and in this case we're just
解决在这种情况下，我们 只是
doing one byte accesses okay so we're
做一个字节访问好了，所以我们
asking the cache to return the byte
要求高速缓存返回字节
that's in this at this physical address
这是在这个在这个物理地址
okay so the cache of course it first
好了，当然它缓存第一
checks to see is that if the byte that's
检查看到的是，如果 字节 这是
requested is contained in some block in
请求中包含的一些块
the cache okay so we
缓存好了，所以我们
so it takes in it extracts the cash
所以需要在它提取现金
index bits which is 0 0 1 0 1 so 5 and
索引比特是0 0 1 0 1 5，以便和
so if this if this byte that's being
因此，如果这如果这个字节是真实存在
requested is in the cache it's going to
要求是它要缓存
be in set 5 so we go to set 5 and then
在5集，所以我们去设定5，然后
we're looking for a tag of 0 XD and lo
我们正在寻找0 XD和LO的标签
and behold here's we have a matching tag
谁知这里的，我们有一个匹配的标签
and about matching valid bit so good the
而关于匹配有效位那么好
line that we're that we request that is
行，我们是，我们要求是
in the cache and the word that the word
在缓存和单词，单词
that we requested is at offset two okay
我们要求在偏移 2好吗
so we go to so this is offset 1 this is
所以我们去所以这个偏移 1这是
offset two oh no I'm sorry
偏移两个OH没有对不起
see what oh I'm sorry it's it I was
看看哦，对不起，这是它我
getting confused the into these are the
感到困惑的进入这些都是
index bits so the offset is actually
索引比特，从而偏移量实际上是
zero here's the business B this is our
这里Zero的的 业务B，这 是我们的
physical address okay and B and the
物理地址好吗和B以及
value of that offset is zero so we're
抵消该 值 是零 ，因此我们
asking for the in the fifth set we're
要求在第五盘我们
asking for the the byte at offset zero
要求该字节偏移量为零
and that's 0 X 3 6 6 so we have a hit
这就是0 X 3 6 6所以我们必须一击
the cash returns that byte back to the
现金返回此字节 回
MMU which which passes it back to the
MMU这其中传递回了
processor which stores it in a register
处理器将其存储在寄存器
most likely ok so let's look at another
最有可能 确定，所以让我们来看看 另一个
example and I've recorded these here for
例如 ，我在这里记录了这些用于
you if you want to go back in and look
你如果想回去看看
at them let's look at another example
他们让我们来 看看另一个例子
this would so this time the CPU sends a
这将所以这个时候CPU发送
virtual address of 0 X 0 0 to 0 to the
的0 X 0 0 0虚拟地址到
MMU okay and so if we if we write out
MMU 可以的，所以如果我们，如果我们 写出来的
the bits for for that virtual address we
对于虚拟 地址，我们 的位
get we get we get this result and then
让我们得到我们得到这样的结果，然后
we've marked off the virtual page offset
我们已经标出关闭虚拟 页偏移
the virtual page number and the TLB
虚拟页码和TLB
index low order bits of the virtual page
虚拟页的索引低位比特
number and the and then the tag for the
数量和，然后为标签
TLB T so as step 1 same as before check
TLBŤ从而步骤1相同，检查之前
with the TLB let's see if that page
与TLB让我们看看该网页
table entries in the TLB T in the in the
在在在TLBŤ表条目
and the TLB so we're asking in this case
与TLB所以我们要求在这种情况下，
this set if this if this page table
如果此集合这一点，如果此页表
entries in the in the TLB it'll be in
项中的TLB 它会在
it'll be in sub-zero and it will have
这将是在零度以下 ， 这 将有
the tag of zero so we look we look and
零的标签，所以我们看我们期待和
set zero for a tag of zero now this
设置为零 的零 标签 现在这
doesn't match oh three years oh nine
不符 哦3年哦9
that doesn't match
不匹配
zero zero matches but the valid bits 0
零轮零散的比赛，但有效位 0
so this isn't a valid entries just a
所以这不仅是一个有效的条目
coincidence that this keg was was 0 so
巧合的是， 这是啤酒桶是 0，所以
this is a TLB miss okay so that's a
这是一个TLB错过 好了，这是一个
bummer because now we have to go off the
无赖，因为现在我们必须去关闭
chip and make an expensive memory access
芯片并进行昂贵的内存访问
just to read that page table entry from
刚读从页表项
the the page table so now we have to so
在页表所以现在我们必须 这样
now we have to check with the page table
现在我们要检查与页表
[Music]
[音乐]
and we're looking for a virtual page
我们正在寻找一个虚拟页
virtual page zero so we check the entry
虚拟页零，所以我们选中的条目
at virtual page zero to see if that page
在零虚拟页面， 看看是否页
except page is in memory and if so if it
除了页面是内存如果是这样，如果它
has a valid is it is in memory because
具有有效的是 它在内存中 ，因为
the valid that's one so this so we have
有效的那一个所以这个，所以我们有
a valid physical page number so the
有效的物理页号，以便在
memory returns the page table entry or
内存返回页表项或
the PPN back to the the back to the mnu
在PPN回的回 MNU
which is a it's a 0 X 0 X 2 8 and now
其是它是一个0 X 0 X 2 8 和现在
the mm you can use that that physical
您可以使用 物理的毫米
page number to construct the physical
页码构建物理
address so as before we copy the virtual
址，才复制虚拟
page offset directly into the physical
页面直接偏移到物理
page offset and then our PT n is is to 8
页面偏移量，然后我们 PT n是是 8
so we have 1 0 its to 1 0 0 0 8
所以，我们有1 0 其1 0 0 0 8
so now concatenated those form the
所以现在这些串接形成
physical address and now the MMU has a
物理 地址 和现在的MMU有
physical address that it can hand off to
物理地址，它可以移交给
the cache and request that the cache
高速缓存和请求缓存
return that value at that at that
在在那个返回值
physical address so now the cache gets
物理地址所以现在缓存得到
that physical address and it extracts
物理地址，并提取
the cache index bits which in this case
缓存索引位，在这种情况下
are 8 k 0 X 8 so if this the block if
是是 8 K 0 X 8，所以如果此块如果
the word that we're looking for is
我们正在寻找的字
contained in the cache I'm sorry if the
包含在高速缓存对不起，如果
byte that we're looking for is contained
我们正在寻找字节包含
in the cache it'll be in set 8 so we go
在缓存中它会在8集 ， 所以 我们去
so the cache goes to set 8 and it looks
所以缓存去设置 8，它看起来
for a matching tag which in this case is
一个匹配的标签，其在这种情况下是
it turns out that it's 28 just like the
事实证明，这28只喜欢
PPN just by coincidence
PPN只是巧合
so in in set eight we have a tag if we
所以在八根，我们有，如果我们一个标签
have an entry the block has a tag of 24
有块有24标记的条目
so there is some is okay so this is a
所以有一些是好的，所以这是一个
cache miss and now the cache has to
高速缓存未命中现在缓存有
request pass that physical address to
请求传递物理地址
the memory to fetch that bite yes how do
该内存是获取该咬伤 怎么办
you see how the question is how do you
你看到的问题是如何是你如何
know how do you determine the size of
知道你是怎么确定的大小
the virtual page offset and yes it's
虚拟页偏移和是的，它是
based on the page size it was 64 bytes
根据页面大小 是64个 字节
so 64 bytes so that's why we have 660 TL
所以64个字节，因此这就是为什么我们有660 TL
and PPO bits
和PPO位
okay so is that clear to everybody that
好了，所以是清楚的 向大家
that's the kind of thing that sometimes
这就是那种东西，有时
turns up on exams you know just
轮番上涨的考试 ，你只知道
yes there is a relationship between the
是的存在之间的关系
length of physical page number and the
的物理页号和长度
cashback that way okay so the question
返现这样 好这样的 问题
is is there any relationship between the
是在那里的任何关系
length of the physical page number and
物理页号的长度和
the cash tag this was just a complete
现金标签 ，这只是一个完整的
coincidence
巧合
okay it just it just happened it was
还好只是 它刚好是
just a coincidence they normally they
只是一个巧合，他们通常它们
don't necessarily have to line up like
不必 排队像
that any other questions yes yes so for
任何其他问题，是的是的 所以
instance if I'd had more sets in my
例如，如果我想在有更多的套我的
cache then I need more bits and they
缓存然后我需要更多的位，他们
spill over right if it's Mike it was
溢出的权利，如果这是迈克是
just a coincidence because I had six ppl
只是一个巧合，因为我有六个PPL
bits and just a block size of four and
位和正好四的块大小 和
four set so if I if my cache had more
四套 所以如果我，如果我的 缓存有更多的
sets that cache index would spill over
设置一个缓存索引，将会波及
and then the cache tag wouldn't match up
然后缓存标签不匹配
with the physical page number okay so it
与物理页号好了，所以它
must be lower like in this occasion
必须 像在这种场合 下
that's that's right it's similar to the
这是这是正确的它是类似
question before it it just happened to
之前，它只是碰巧问题
be a coincidence maybe I should have
是巧合 ，也许 我应该有
chosen a different example but they're
选择了不同的 例子，但他们
completely independent
完全 独立
everybody else good okay
其他人好没关系
okay so now I want to I want to talk to
好了，所以现在我想我想跟
you about how how this stuff all works
你如何如何这些东西全部作品
in a real system in this case it's a
在这种情况下 ，真正的系统它是一个
core i7 system from Intel to next 86 64
从英特尔核i7 系统到下一个 86 64
it's a family of high-end desktop
它的高端台式机的家庭
systems x86 64 there are similar to the
系统x86的64 有类似于
the shark machines that you use to do
您用来做鲨鱼机
your labs
您的实验室
so here's the here's the way the memory
所以这里的，这里的 方式存储
system looks in in the core i7 the
系统会在酷睿i7 的
processor package is the chip okay so
处理器封装是芯片 好了，所以
that's like a single and then and then
这就像一个单一的，然后 再
there's four cores in this package each
有四个内核中的每个这个包
core is a separate as a separate CPU and
核心是一个单独的作为一个单独的CPU和
canary executes instructions separately
金丝雀单独执行指令
okay so each core each each of these
好了，所以每个每个核心各自 的这些
cores has a register file and then a
核心具有寄存器文件， 然后
some hardware that status' instructions
一些硬件状态的指示
it has two l1 caches there's a data
它有两个L1高速缓存有一个数据
cache called the D cache which is used
缓存称为其用于对D高速缓存
to fetch data and which holds data
来获取数据和保持数据
fetched from memory and then there's an
从内存中取出，然后有一个
instruction cache called an AI cache
指令缓存称为AI缓存
which holds instructions that's from the
其中认为从的说明
code the code region so data this D
码的代码区域 ，从而数据 该 D
cache has data only the AI cache has
缓存有数据只有AI缓存有
instructions only there each 32 K bytes
说明仅存在每个32千个字节
8 way set associative so they're very
8路组相联，使他们感到 非常
small but they have fairly high
小，但 它们有相当高的
associativity and then the next level in
关联再下 一级
the hierarchy is a an l2 so called
层次是所谓的L2
unified cache because it can hold both
统一高速缓存，因为它可以同时按住
instructions and data okay it's a little
指令和数据好 这是一个有点
bit bigger 256 K bytes and also
大一点的256千个字节，也
eight-way associative and so both of
八路关联 等两个
these caches are on the on the core
这些缓存是在对核心
itself ok and then outside and enters an
本身确定，然后外并进入
l3 cache which is shared by all cores
这是由所有 内核 共享的L3高速缓存
which is 8 megabytes and 16 white
其是8兆字节和16 白色
associative ok so the access is because
联想确定这样的访问是因为
the l1 cache is closest to the processor
L1高速缓存是最靠近处理器
this is this is fast this is like four
这是，这是快这样四
cycles to access l1 l2 is bigger and a
周期来访问L1 L2是更大和一个
little further away so it the it's about
稍远一点，使其与它有关
10 10 cycles to access this and l3 is
10 10 个周期访问此 和13是
off the core right so it has to go over
关闭核心权利，因此必须走了过来
a
一个
a connection some connection off the off
连接 部分连接关关
the chip into this into this cache and
芯片 进入到这个这个 缓存 和
so the the access time for this l3 cache
因此，访问时间为这个 L3缓存
it's like 50 30 to 50 cycles now the the
它现在的像50 30〜50次
MMU has it also has a hierarchy of TLDs
MMU 有它也有 顶级域名 的层次结构
and I was talking with a student after
而我与学生交谈后，
class the last lecture like I mistakenly
类中的 最后演讲就像 我误
said that the the system didn't have a
说，该系统没有一个
hierarchy of tlbs but it does there's a
TLB中的层次结构，但它确实有一个
small l1 data TLB and a and a separate
小的L1数据TLB 和一个和一个单独的
instruction TLB so the this has 16 64
指令TLB所以这具有16 64
total entries and it's 4-way set
总条目和它的4路集
associative so how many sets are there
联想这么多少套在 那里
then in this how many sets in the l1
然后在L1这多少套
data TLB
数据TLB
sixteen right good and then the the
16 右好， 然后将
instruction TLB has more entries
指令TLB有多个条目
interestingly so it's it's an
有趣所以它是一个
interesting decision I guess the I guess
有趣的决定我 猜我猜
the thinking I don't I don't really know
思维我不我真的不 知道
I'm just trying to conjecturing that the
我只是试图揣测的是，
reason they would make the instruction
他们之所以会做出指示
TLB bigger suspect that the penalty for
TLB更大的犯罪嫌疑人的处罚
missing on instructions would be much
缺少说明会更
larger but yeah I'm not sure it's an
较大，但亲爱的，我不知道 它是一个
interesting decision and then there's a
有趣的决定，然后有一个
there's a unified TLB below that which
有一个统一的TLB低于其
is a larger larger still so the I think
是一个较大的仍较大，因此，我认为
if you're wondering I mean it's
如果你想知道我的意思是
interesting to think like why do they
有趣的这样想为什么他们
have these like the second level caches
有这些类似的二级高速缓存
why didn't they just make these l2 l1
为什么他们不只是让这些 L1 L2
caches bigger right and in the case of
缓存 更大的权利和的情况下，
the in the case of the D cache and the I
将在D缓存和 我的情况下，
cache over here I'll show you in just a
缓存在这里我会告诉你在 短短的
little bit if you hang on there's a
如果 你挂在有一 点点
really interesting reason why they can't
真正有趣的原因，他们不能
make these things bigger or much bigger
让这些事情变大或更大
right there there's a so there's there's
在那里有一个这么有有
there's a property of the they're sort
还有的属性有几分
of constrained in the in the size of the
的 约束在中的大小
offset and index bits in these these
偏移和 在这些这些 索引位
caches if it's interesting I'll show you
如果缓存也同样吸引 我会告诉你
in a second for the through the TLB knee
在通过TLB膝盖的第二对
I mean one reason that comes to mind for
我的意思是 我想到的一个 原因
why they didn't why they had the second
为什么他们没有，为什么他们有第二
level is that if they decided just to
水平，如果他们决定只是为了
make the l1 data D TLB and ITL B's
使L1数据 D TLB和 ITL B的
bigger you know take the take the
长大了，你知道拿拿
transistors that they used for this l2
他们用于 此L2晶体管
and and just give them to the level one
并且，只是给他们一个水平
TLB s it you kind of by partitioning
TLB 由分区的IT 你有种
those by partitioning those those that
那些通过分割那些那些
storage ahead of time you're kind of
存储的时间提前你是那种
walking yourself in so it
走自己所以
if you didn't have this level two TLB
如果你没有这个二级TLB
and and you just increase say you gave
而你只是增加 说 你给
half and so it made L 1 and L the data
一半，所以它由L 1和L中的数据
TLB an instruction TLB twice as big then
TLB 指令TLB 两倍大，然后
you're sort of locking yourself in right
你是那种把自己锁在右
- if if you run you might run out of you
- 如果你运行你可能会遇到你了
still might run out of instructions and
仍可能会耗尽指示和
have capacity misses in that in that l1
在这种能力缺失在L1
cache I'm saying similarly for data
缓存我在说同样的数据
right so you're not sure you may in a
右所以你 不知道，你可以在
particular program there may bake there
特定的程序有可能有烤
may be a lot more data page table
可能很多更多的数据页表
entries the instruction page table
项指令页表
entries in order vice versa so by by
为了 副条目反之亦然所以通过
creating the second level of cache
创建缓存的第二个层次
you're kind of hedging your bets right
你有种对冲你的赌注 权
so you may the Miss penalty when you
所以，你可能小姐 罚你的时候
have this l2 cache the Miss penalty in
有这样的L2高速缓存的缺失损失 在
l1 isn't nearly as big as it would be if
L1是不是几乎一样大，这将是，如果
because if you didn't okay so that
因为如果你这样做不好吧，这样
that's sort of the thinking that goes on
这就是那种那张思维
now there's a there's a memory
现在有一个有记忆
controller which count which fetches
控制器，其计数，其取
data from memory and then there's links
从 内存中 的数据 ， 然后有联系
to other cores into the i/o bridge
给其他核 到I / O 桥
now and 2n so it's really interesting so
现在和2N所以这真的很有趣所以
it's interesting to see how this all
这是有趣的， 看看 这 一切 是如何
fits together and to end
组合在一起并结束
so let's look let's look at it so the
所以让我们来看看让我们来 看看它，因此
CPU generates a virtual address in Intel
CPU生成在英特尔的虚拟地址
systems the virtual addresses are 48
系统 虚拟地址是48
bits with 4k sized blocks so 12 offset
与4K 大小的块的比特，以便偏移12
bits and then 36 VPN bits so first we
位，然后36 位的VPN因此首先我们
look in the in the cache I mean in the
看在高速缓存中的我的意思是在
TLB and there's as we said before
TLB 和我们之前所说有
there's 16 TLB sets this is the l1 I'm
有16 TLB设置，这是 我的L1
showing the l1 data TLB so we break it
显示L1数据TLB，所以我们打破它
up into 4 TLB I index bits and 32 tag
成 4个TLB I指数比特 和32标签
bits so we do a lookup on the in the TLB
位，所以我们做了查找的在TLB
to see if we can find that the Pte that
看看我们是否能够发现 私人那
contains that the corresponding physical
包含对应的物理
page number for this virtual address if
这个 虚拟地址 ，如果页号
we have a hit then the MMU can just
我们有一个命中，则 MMU可以只
construct the physical address directly
直接构造的物理地址
by copying as we saw before copying the
通过复制，因为我们复制以前看到
gpo to the PPO and then using the TPN
GPO的PPO，然后使用TPN
that was returned from the TLB
这是从TLB返回
how's that for now a credenza
是不是这样，现在书柜
if there's a TLB miss then the system
如果有一个TLB失败，则系统
has to fetch the corresponding PT PP n
具有获取相应的 PT PP N
from the page table using that multi way
从使用 多路 页表
lookup we looked multi level lookup we
查找我们看多层次查找我们
looked at before out and I'll show you
看着面前 了，我会 告诉 你
how this works in a little more detail
这是如何工作的更详细一点
coming up but the end result is that a
来了，但最终的结果是，
page table entry is located and the PP n
页表项位于和 PP N
is extracted from that and concatenated
从该提取和串接
with the PP o to form the physical
与PPÒ以形成 物理
address then the MMU passes that
解决则MMU通过 该
physical address to the cache the l1
物理地址缓存L1
data cache has 64 sets so we need six
数据缓存有64套，所以我们需要 六
cache index bits now here's what I was
现在 缓存索引位 这里就是我
alluding to before notice that the
通知之前暗指的是，
number of cache index and cache offset
缓存索引 和高速缓存 的数量偏移
bits is exactly identical to the VPO in
位是完全相同的VPO在
the virtual address okay so the the
虚拟地址好吗所以在
cache offset and index bits in the
在高速缓存偏移和索引位
physical address are identical to the
物理地址是相同的
the VPO the offset bits and the virtual
所述VPO偏移位和虚拟
address okay and this is not a
解决好了，这是不是一个
coincidence okay unlike that other
巧合 不像其他 还好
example I showed you this is not a
例如我发现你这是不是 一个
coincidence and this is this is at the
巧合，这是 这是在
root this is at the root of why the l1
根这是为什么L1的根
caches is so small that the way the way
缓存是如此之小，设置三路
until implements their cache lookups
直到实现自己的高速缓存查找
which we'll see in a second
我们将在第二个看
depends on the cache index and cache
依赖于缓存索引和缓存
offset bits and the physical address
偏移位与物理地址
being identical to the offset bits and
是 相同于偏移的位和
the virtual address
虚拟地址
anyway so then we do our cash we do our
反正所以后来我们做我们的现金我们做我们的
cache look up using the the cash doesn't
高速缓存查找使用现金 不
look up using the using this physical
查找使用使用这个物理
adjusts takes the index bits to identify
调整取索引位来标识
asset uses the tag to see if there's a
资产 使用的标签，看看是否有一个
match if there is then we have a hit
匹配，如果有那么我们有一击
which returns the resulting word back to
其返回 结果背单词
the CPU otherwise there's a miss so then
在CPU 否则有一个 小姐这样的话
the cache has to request the data from
高速缓存必须 从请求数据
l2 l3 and main memory eventually worst
，L2，L3和主存储器最终最差
case that that data comes from main
该数据来自主要情况
memory so I guess worst case it comes
记忆，所以我想最坏的情况下它涉及
from disk right page miss page low so
从盘右页错失页 这么低
eventually though the data the data
虽然最终的数据数据
comes back and is returned back to the
回来并返回到
CPU now that the page table entries on
CPU是现在的页表项上
in Intel systems have the following
在Intel 系统具有以下
structure you can see that the the level
结构，你可以看到水平
the level 1 page which levels the level
1 级 页面，其级别水平
1 through 3 pages remember that that
1〜3页记得那
page table entry points to the address
页表项指向 的 地址
of the next level page table ok so it
下一级页表的确定，所以它
contains the level 1 the level 1 PT e
包含1级1级PTË
contains the base address the physical
包含基地址的 物理
address of the level 2 table and so on
2级表 的地址等
there's a there's a bit this is the
有一个有一点 是 这样 的
valid bit they call it the P VP for
他们把它叫做P VP为有效位
present so this identifies whether that
本所以这种识别是否该
the page is in memory or not if it's not
该页面是在内存中还是没有 ，如果它不是
then it's then there's a location of it
然后它再有它的 位置
of that page table on disk
在 磁盘 页表
there's bits to control whether the that
有位来控制是否是
page table can be read is the read only
页表可以读取只能读
or it can be written so actually this
或可 其实 这 这么 写 的
corresponds to all reachable pages so
对应于所有可到达的网页，以便
you know you can show all reachable
你知道你可以 显示所有可到达
pages so all of the portion of the
网页，以便所有 的部分
address space that's covered by this
多数民众赞成这个涵盖的地址空间
particular page table entry there's also
特别是页表项有也
a bit that indicates whether users can
一个位，表明用户能否
can access that or if they need to be
可以访问或者如果他们需要
running in kernel mode so this this is
在内核模式下运行，所以这是这个
how the kernel protects its code and
内核是如何保护其代码和
data from from user programs there's a
从用户程序的数据有一个
there's a bit here to indicate whether
有一点这里指示是否
we should be using write back or write
我们应该使用 回 写 或 写
through for this for these page tables
通过此这些页表
and all systems I know of use use right
和所有的系统我知道的使用使用权
back just because of the Miss penalty
回来只是因为小姐处罚
the enormous miss penalty forget what CD
巨大的命中损失 忘记CD
does there's a there's a reference bit
确实有一个有一个参考位
which is set when the MMU reads or
其中当MMU读取或设置
writes reads or writes that pit the the
写入读取或写入该坑的
page table at this points to and there's
在此页表指向和有
and then there's a there's a bit that
再有一个有一点是
indicates whether the page size is
表示页面大小 是否
either four K bytes or four megabytes
任一4 千个字节或四兆字节
okay and then there's this there's this
好吧，然后有这个还有这个
new disabled it's the XD bit which which
新的禁用它的XD位哪家
disables allows you to disable or enable
禁用允许您禁用或启用
execution from all the pages reachable
从所有到达的页面执行
from that page table entry so this is
从页表项，所以这是
how the stack modern systems protect the
堆栈现代系统如何保护
stack from code injection attacks
从代码注入攻击堆栈
okay the last level page table entry
还好最后一级页表项
points to a fork it points to not
指向它指向的不是一个叉
another page table but actually a page
另一页表，但实际上一个页面
in memory and so the same we have the
在内存中，所以同样的，我们 有
same bits here the same 40 bits that
这里 同位 相同的40个比特
that give the physical address of that
该给的物理地址
page in memory and then we have the
在内存页，然后我们有
indication of whether that page is is
的该页面是否是指示
present in memory or not and the rewrite
存在于存储器中或不和重写
and and permission execute permission
并和权限执行权限
bits right through our right back
正确的通过 我们的右后卫 位
there's a reference there's this
有一个 参考有这
reference bit and then there's a dirty
参考位，然后有一个肮脏的
bit which the MMU sets when it writes to
位该MMU设置时将其写入
that page okay so this is how this is
该页面好 了，这是怎么了，这 是
how the OLS knows that it needs to when
在 OLS 如何 知道它需要 时
it selects this if it selects this pages
它选择这个，如果它选择此页
of victim it it looks at the dirty bit
受害人它看起来在脏位
to see if it needs to write that page
看它是否 需要 编写一个页面
back do you have a question
回你有一个问题
execute means that you can't execute any
执行意味着你不能执行任何
instructions you can't load any
你无法加载任何指示
instructions from that page okay the
从该页面没关系的说明
this user or supervisor mode in
该用户或管理员模式中
determines whether you can access that
决定您是否可以访问
page so if it's set to supervisor mode
所以，如果它被设置为管理员模式下页
only the kernel can can access that page
只有 内核可以可以访问该页面
anything on that page if it's set to you
该网页上的任何东西，如果它被设置为您
then anybody user code and kernel code
那么任何人用户代码和内核代码
can access that page the only questions
可以访问该网页的唯一 问题
okay so then the the way it does address
好了，那么它的方式确实解决
translation then is the physical for
然后翻译是物理的
this process so the kernel for each
这个过程使内核为 每
process maintains the you know set of
进程维护你知道设定的
page tables of course and then it in it
当然，页表，然后在它
maintains the address of the first L 1
保持第一L 1 的地址
table in a register called CR 3 okay and
表在称为CR 3行寄存器和
this is a physical address plates to the
这是 一个 物理地址板到
base of the level 1 page table the the
1 级 页表 的基的的
VPN is broken up into 36 divided by 4
VPN被分成36除以4
equals 9 bits that gives offsets into
等于9位，让的偏移 到
each page table entry
每个页表项
okay so so there's two to the ninth
好了，所以有两到第九
potential page table entries in each in
在每一个潜在的页表项
each pay in each of these different page
在这些不同的页面的每个交
tables so the this VPN one is used the
表所以该VPN一个被使用的
high order nine bits are used to compute
高阶九个位被 用来计算
an offset into the into that table and
中的偏移量成表和
you can see each each level one PT II
每个你可以看到每个级别一个PT II
covers a swath of memory that's 512
占地内存大片这512
gigabytes in size so you can see for
GB的大小，所以你可以看到
most most programs that exist today
今天存在最大多数程序
you only need one level one page table
你只需要一个 一级页表
entry this to be initialized that would
进入这个被初始化，将
cover you know the vast majority of your
覆盖你知道绝大多数的 你
programs the the next nine bits it okay
节目也 没关系下九位
so the page table entry in the level 1
因此在级别1中的页表项
the page table points to the it gives
页表指向它给
the physical address of the level 2 page
2级页面的物理地址
table and then the VPN bits in the
表，然后在该VPN位
virtual address are used to compute an
虚拟地址时，用于计算
offset into that table and so on it just
偏移成表等它只是
cascades and then finally the last the
级联，最后的最后一个
low order of bits of the nine bits of
九个比特位的低位
the VPN are used to form an offset into
该VPN 被用于形成一个偏移
the level four page table which in which
四级页表，在 其中
each each PT e points to an actual page
每个每个PTè指向实际页面
it gives a physical page number so then
它给出了一个物理页号码，然后
that that physical page number then is
这则物理页号
extracted and concatenated with the VPO
萃取，并用所述VPO级联
which we copied down to form a physical
我们复制下来，形成一个物理
address
地址
okay today everybody good okay now
还好今天大家现在好了好了
there's this there's this cool trick
还有的这个有这个很酷的技巧
which I was alluding to earlier that
我为这暗指 早些时候
limits the size of l1 cache now to this
现在限制L1缓存的大小， 这个
point we've been we've been using a
一点上，我们一直在我们一直使用
model where the the MMU
模型，其中的MMU
takes the verge does address translation
采用边缘做地址转换
and creates a complete virtual address a
并创建一个完整的虚拟地址
physical address and then it sends that
物理地址， 然后发送该
physical address to the cache okay but
物理地址缓存不错，但
in reality intel does this cute trick to
在现实英特尔不对这个可爱的把戏
speed up l1 cache accesses so what in
加快L1缓存访问等 什么的
reality what happens so we're given a
所以我们既定 现实会发生什么
virtual address okay and in this virtual
虚拟 地址 很好，而且在这个虚拟
address the index and off the physical
解决索引和关闭物理
the index and offset that's in the
索引和 偏移这是在
physical address are identical exactly
物理地址是相同的准确
correspond to the PP o in the physical
对应于PP o在物理
address which is exactly identical to
地址是完全相同
the DPO in the virtual address so that
该DPO 虚拟地址，以便
means is that when the the MMU is given
手段是，当给出的MMU
a virtual address it can send the VPO
虚拟地址 就可以发送VPO
off to the l1 cache even though it's a
截止到即使它是 一个 L1缓存
even though l1 is is this is physically
即使L1是是，这是物理
addressed we can send that the VPO in
寻址我们可以发送 的VPO在
the virtual address to the l1 cache
虚拟地址 到 L1 缓存
because of this because of this
因为这一点，因为 这
phenomenon that the the TPO is identical
现象， 即 该 TPO是相同
to the VPO so even before the MMU is
在VPO所以即使之前的MMU是
doing any address translation it can
做任何地址转换可以
send this these these VPO bits to the
发送此这些这些VPO位的
cache and then the cache can get busy
缓存，然后缓存可以去忙
extracting the index the cache index
提取索引缓存索引
bits looking up you know looking up all
比特仰视你知道所有仰视
of the the lines in that in that set and
在该组中的所述线与
then have everything ready for the tag
然后把一切都准备了 标签
check which can only occur after the
检查哪些可以后才会出现
address translation should happen so it
地址转换应该发生，因此
can only occur once there's a physical
曾经有一个物理才会发生
address with a from which we can extract
以从中我们可以提取解决
the
该
cash tag so this so there's a little bit
现金标签所以这所以有一点点
of parallelism now in the l1 cache
L1缓存 现在并行
accesses so we can be the mmm you can be
存取 所以我们可以 ，你可以是 MMM
doing address translation while the the
做地址转换，而在
l1 cache gets going on it it's lookup
L1缓存大干快上它， 它的 查找
okay so now let's look at how Linux
好吧所以现在让我们来看看 Linux 如何
implements virtual virtual memory and in
实现虚拟虚拟内存和在
doing so will now get a clearer
这样做现在 得到 更加清晰
understanding of how fork and exec and
了解如何fork和exec和
loading really work okay so we've seen
装载真的好吗工作，所以我们看到的
this pictures of picture like this
此图片的画面像这样的
several times before this is the virtual
前 几次 ，这是虚拟
address space of the Linux process
在Linux进程 的地址空间
because we have because of the way the
因为我们 的 ， 因为 路
virtual memory system works every
虚拟内存系统每天都要工作
process has a very similar-looking
过程中有一个非常相似的外观
address space that program text the code
地址空间程序文本 代码
is always loaded at the same 0 X 400,000
总是被加载在 相同的0 X 400000
address and that's followed by
解决而 这之后
initialized data which comes from the
这来自 初始化 数据
dot data section of the of the
的的点数据部
executable binary and then there's the
可执行的二进制，然后还有的
BSS section which contains uninitialized
BSS段包含未初始化
data that was that was defined in the
这是这是在所定义的数据
binary and then the heat then the heat
二进制， 然后将热则热
grows up from from the initialized data
从初始化数据向上增长
there it's pointed to by a global
有它的指向全球
variable called in a global variable in
变量称为 全局变量
this process context called break so the
这个所谓的休息，以便进程上下文
kernel keeps track of where the top of
内核跟踪顶部的地方
the heap is for this this process
堆是此这个过程
there's a memory mapped region for
有一个内存映射区域
shared libraries and then at the top of
共享库，然后在顶部
the users the user level user
用户的用户级别的用户
user-accessible memory there's this user
用户可访问的内存有该用户
stack which grows down which is pointed
栈增长下降，这是尖
to by rst and then the that the kernel
通过第一个，然后内核
code and data live up in the upper
代码和数据不辜负在上
portion of the address space
地址空间的一部分
now this picture isn't completely
现在这幅画不完全
accurate there's actually like a big gap
准确居然还有像一个很大的差距
between the top of the stack and the
堆的 顶部 和之间
beginning of the the kernel code and
开始的内核代码和
data I'm the reason for that is that the
数据我之所以说是，
Intel Architecture says that that so
英特尔架构说，有这么
there's 48 virtual address bits so if
有48 虚拟地址位，所以如果
that's it's the high-order bit of that
这就是它 的了 高位
48 bit address is 0 then all the all the
48位的地址为0，则所有的所有
remaining bits have to be 0 all of the
剩余的位必须 是0的所有 的
all of the height the remaining endure
所有高度的其余忍受
of the 64 high-order bits need to be 0
64 高阶 位需要是0
so it's kind of like sign extension
所以它有点像符号扩展
right and if that if that high-order bit
权利，如果说如果 高位
in the 48 bit address is 1 then you
在48位地址为1，那么你
extend the 1 all the way up to the
延长1点一路 攀升 到
remaining high-order bits okay so those
剩余的高序位好了，所以那些
are the only feasible yet so what that
是唯一可行 又那么是什么
does is it creates a the two kernels
所做的就是创建 一个以两个内核
living the kernels living in in a
居住生活在一个内核
portion of the virtual address space
虚拟 地址空间 的一部分
where that the 12 the 12 high order bits
其中，该12的 12位高位比特
are all ones okay so that creates so you
都还好所有的人，以便创造，所以你
can think of it this is the kernel lives
可以认为它是这样的内核生活
in the very top of the 64 64-bit address
在64的64位地址的最顶端
space okay
空间好吗
another way to think of it in Colonel
另一种方式把它的 上校
addresses always start with one the most
地址总是以一个最开始
significant bit is 1 and user addresses
显著位 为1个用户地址
always have a most significant bit of
总是有最显著位
zero that's just the detail doesn't
零那只是 没有详细
doesn't really affect things but Whitten
并没有真正影响的事情，但 惠顿
what is important is that this this is
最重要的是，这，这是
the process virtual address space of a
的过程中的虚拟地址空间
process right and so the kernel exists
程序的权利 等的内核中存在
in the virtual address space of each
在每个虚拟地址空间
process in it so there's there's kernel
在这过程中所以有有内核
code and data and then it also Maps it
代码和数据，然后它也 映射 它
has a region of its virtual address
有其虚拟地址的区
space that map's each element of this of
该地图的 这的 每个 元素空间
this region with an address in physical
此区域在物理地址
memory ok so that this this mapping this
内存好了，所以，这 本该映射
region is corresponds to the amount of
区域对应于量
DRAM on the chip and so it's a mechanism
DRAM芯片上 ，所以它是一个 机制
that the kernel uses to get access to
该内核使用以访问
physical addresses ok and this is
物理地址确定，这是
important because remember the kernel
重要的，因为记得内核
there you can never you can't turn off
在那里，你永远不能，你不能关闭
address translation right it's always
地址转换的权利，它总是
happening ok even even when the kernel
发生OK甚至即使 内核
runs the address translation is
运行地址 转换
happening the kernel is generating
发生内核生成
virtual addresses so this this this this
虚拟地址所以这这这这
region this is map to a region of the
区域，这是地图 的 一个区域
physical memory so that if if the kernel
物理内存 ，因此如果你的核心
access is bytes 0 of this of this block
访问是 这一这个块的 字节0
it will it will actually be the theme
将它 实际上 将 成为主题
speed the the address that the
加快地址的
corresponding physical address will be 0
对应的物理地址为0
and if it accesses a byte at an offset
如果它在访问一个字节偏移
of 1 in this region the physical address
在该区域 1 的物理地址
the corresponding physical address from
从相应的物理地址
the address translation process will be
地址转换的过程会
1 ok so basically by reading and writing
1 确定 ，所以基本上通过阅读和写作
into this region the kernel is reading
进入这个区域 的核心是阅读
and writing into physical memory and
并写入到物理内存和
this so there's portions of the kernel
这所以有内核的部分
that are identical for every process
是对每一个工艺相同
right the codes the same it's not in but
右边的代码一样它不是，但
then there's there's process specific
再有就是有特定的过程
data structures that that the kernel
数据结构，内核
maintains for each process that for
维护每个过程， 对于
in the context for that process so we
在该进程的背景下，所以我们
refer to these and refer to all these
提及这些 ，并指所有这些
with all these data structures as the
所有这些数据结构为
context and these of course have to be
背景和这些当然必须是
these would be different for each
这些将是为每个不同
process now Linux org organizes this
流程现在的Linux组织举办本
virtual address region as a collection
作为一个集合的虚拟地址区域
of what it calls areas in areas like a
其称之为领域 就像一个 领域
segment think of it it's just a chunk of
段想起来它只是一个块
a contiguous chunk of related memory
相关存储器的邻接块
items so the there's a there's an area
项目因此有一个有一个区域
for code there's an area for data shared
用于代码 有用于共享数据的区域
libraries have areas there's an area for
图书馆有区有一个区域
the stack and it it contains a there's a
堆栈，它包含 一个有一个
structure for each process called the
结构对于每个过程称为
task task struct and this contains a
任务的任务结构 ，这包含了
pointer to the MM struct which has a
指针MM结构，其具有
bunch of stuff in it but the it contains
一堆东西在里面 ，但它包含
these the address of the level one page
在一级页面 ，这些地址
table okay so that's part of the context
表好了， 这就是 环境 的一部分
when this process runs when this process
在此过程中运行 时，这个过程
is scheduled the kernel will take this
定内核将借此
entry
条目
this PGD entry and he'll copy it into
这PGD项，他将其复制到
cr3 okay so that's how it switches just
CR3好了，这是它 只是 切换
by changing the cr3 register the kernel
通过改变 CR3寄存器内核
changes the address space so that's how
改变了地址空间，所以这是 怎么
and once once that once that cr3 value
一旦一旦一旦CR3值
is changed then the process no longer
随后改变的过程不再
has access to the previous processes
访问前步骤
page tables right so and then there's a
页表右边左右，然后有一个
and then there's a pointer to a list of
然后有一个指针列表
these these so-called area structs the
这些这些 所谓的 区域结构的
area struct identifies the start at the
区域结构确定了在开始
beginning and end of the region any
开始，该地区的任何结束
protections like is this read-only
保护像 这是只读
region for example so the code the code
区域例如，使代码的代码
section would be set as read-only or is
部分将被设置为只读， 或者是
it read/write and then there's some
它的读/写，然后有一些
other some other flags which
其它一些其他的标志，其
see which we'll see later
看到我们将在后面看到
in particular when we when we look at
特别是当我们的时候，我们 看一下
sharing and mapping for our purposes
共享和映射我们的目的
these these flag bits tell us whether
这些这些标志位告诉我们，无论是
the page is shared with other processes
该网页与其他进程共享
or whether it's private to this this
或者 它 是否 为 私有 此
process so normally the default is that
过程因此通常默认的 是，
pages are all private but you have the
页面都是 私人 ，但你有
option if you do if you do a fair amount
选择，如果你做，如果你做了相当多
of work you can get prophecies to share
工作的，你可以得到 预言分享
to share memory okay so let's look at
共享内存 好了，让我们来 看看
what happens when we have a page fault
当我们有一个页面错误 ，会发生什么
so let's say so there's you know the
让我们这样说有，你知道的
processor issues an instruction the
处理器发出的指令，
adjust translation process determines
调节翻译过程确定
that the correspondent page isn't
该记者页面不
contained in memory so it triggers a
包含在内存中，因此它会触发 一个
page fault and so the fault handler
缺页等故障处理程序
there's several there's several things
有几个有几件事情
that might have happened one maybe we
可能已经发生了 ，也许我们 一个
were reading memory it faulted because
正在读内存故障是由于
that that memory that area doesn't even
该内存该区域甚至不
exist
存在
we haven't even created the kernel
我们甚至还没有创建的内核
hasn't even created allocated that that
甚至还没有创建分配的那
page in virtual memory yet okay so
在虚拟内存页面还好吧，
that's an error
这是一个错误
so that's accessing a non-existing page
所以这访问 不存在的页面
elicits a seg fault so the kernel
，诱发赛格故障所以内核
figures that out because it runs down
说出来，因为它运行下来的数字
this list of of area structs and it it
区域结构的这个名单， 它是
doesn't find this address anywhere
任何地方都不会找到这个地址，
within the ranges of those areas so
这些区域的范围内，从而
that's that's a seg fault act caused by
就是这样的引起的赛格故障行为
accessing a non-existing page another
访问 不存在的页面另一
possibility is that the instruction is
可能是该指令
attempting to write into a read-only
试图写入到一个只读的
section segment of the virtual address
将虚拟地址的部分分段
space well they this that there's
空间以及他们这一点，有
nothing in the page table the MMU
没有在页表的MMU
typically would check the the permission
通常会检查权限
bits in the in the page table entry and
在位页表项和
throw an exception if the right is
抛出一个异常，如果正确的是
trying to to write to a read-only page
试图写入只读页
but in this case that there was no page
但在这种情况下，有没有页面
table entry right into trick that's why
表项直接进入招，这就是为什么
I triggered a page fault
我触发页面错误
so the MMU doesn't know that this is an
所以MMU不知道这是一个
illegal right
非法权
the colonel can check the protection for
上校 可以检查保护
this area and if it's in the kit in the
这方面，如果它在该套件
case of text that will be set to read
文本的情况下，将 设置为read
only so that triggers a protection
只有这样触发保护
exception which actually Linux reports
除了这实际上Linux的报告
as a segfault and then then the other
作为一个段错误 ，然后再另
option is that maybe we're trying to
选择是，也许我们正在 努力
read data from a valid from a valid area
从有效区域读取的有效数据
so then the kernel false that the
所以那么内核假的
requested page in and and returns to the
请求的页面中，并返回到
requested data back to the back to the
请求的数据返回到回
CPU okay the last thing I want to look
CPU 好吧，我想 看看 过去的事情
at today is is it yes okay ask sorry
今天是是是 好问对不起
yeah so all of the segments are
是啊，这样所有的段都
contained in the executable file okay
包含在可执行文件好吗
there's a at the at the beginning of the
有一个在在的开始
elf binary there's a list of all the all
小精灵二进制还有所有的所有的列表
the different segments okay so when it
不同的细分好了，所以当它
when it when eggs act loads the binary
当它 当鸡蛋充当载荷 二进制
creates it creates areas for each of
创建它的每一个领域创造
those each of those segments
那些每个那些段的
oh good yes so how many are construct
哦，好的是那么有多少是构建
like you
喜欢你
Louis's Lee is still first hit lately
路易斯的李尚属首创 最近打
does that immunity interest like one day
的确免疫力的兴趣如一日
this is after the page fault yes the MMU
这是页面故障后是在MMU
doesn't know about these okay so yeah
不知道这些好所以是
the question is exactly how are these
问题是究竟如何是这些
arias trucks used and they're used
用咏叹调卡车，他们正在使用
they're used in this in this content in
他们 在这个使用这个内容
this example anyway they're used during
这个例子 反正 他们在习惯
the page faults okay and and also just
该页面错误很好，而且也只是
as a an aside I shown these actually are
作为题外话I所示这些实际上是
implemented as lists but in the real
如 列表 ，但在现实中实现
system they
他们系统